# Joseph W. Hull, P.E.

5912 Westover Drive • Knoxville, TN 37919 (865) 406-6692 • joewhull@gmail.com

## **Objective**

I am a senior structural engineer and licensed Professional Engineer (TN) with nine years of progressive experience in design, process improvement, task leadership and project management. I am seeking challenging career opportunities in the fields of civil engineering, structural engineering, construction, plant operations, and project management.

### **Education, Licenses and Certifications**

Jan. 2017	Professional Engineer (Civil) Lic. 117075, Tennessee
Jun. 2007	Engineer-In-Training Lic. 26049, Tennessee Department of Commerce and Insurance
May 2007	<b>B.Sc. in Civil Engineering</b> , The University of Tennessee at Knoxville

### **Professional Experience**

2011–pres.

### Senior Structural Engineer at MS TECHNOLOGY INC. (Y-12 NSC / UPF)

As a senior structural engineer working on the Y-12 National Security Complex Uranium Processing Facility, I was responsible for management of a multi-disciplinary team of engineers and designers ensuring that project milestones are met as part of a \$6.5B nuclear design project. Management responsibilities included preparation of project reports on pipe/structure seismic interaction and equipment seismic qualification, as well as driving necessary engineering design and process improvements to facilitate efficient production of deliverables resulting in project cost savings. Daily responsibilities also involved assisting and mentoring junior engineers. Project management involvement included estimation, scheduling, assignment, tracking of design activities, and reviewing interdiscipline and vendor submittals.

Structures designed included platform structures and multi-story modular structures supporting turn-key systems comprised of mechanical, EI&C, process equipment and piping using carbon and stainless steel; these designs involved preparing, checking, and verifying structural calculations, drawings and 3D modeling as well as disposition of field change requests and safely performing field walkdowns. Design work performed involved extensive use of GT STRUDL including dynamic, linear, time-history analysis, and producing in-structure response spectra. Creation of calculation templates for torsional analysis of open steel section and numerous structural connections. Software utilized also involved testing, verification, and validation to ensure quality.

Joseph W. Hull 2

## Professional Experience (cont'd)

2008-2011

### Civil/Structural Engineer at Bechtel Power Corp. (TVA Watts Bar 2)

For the Watts Bar Unit 2 project I was responsible for the scheduling, management, and completion of all Civil design packages for the Unit 2 Reactor Building and Turbine Building. In this role I also interfaced regularly with the client, vendors, sub-contractors, field engineers, craft, and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Towards project completion I aggressively pursued closure of the Task Engineering effort and supported all disciplines to ensure compliance, uniformity, and expedition of deliverables while also participating in a Six-Sigma team to streamline the issuance of design packages for an estimated project savings of \$1-2 million. I completed the Bechtel Supervisory Development Program.

As an individual contributor I generated structural design packages including design calculations and drawings and prepared nuclear licensing/technical basis documents for retrofitting steel connections on safety-related structures. Designed components and structures included steel platforms, equipment supports, base plates, concrete anchors, reinforced concrete pads and footings and other miscellaneous civil commodities. Design documents I produced included preparing, checking, and verifying design calculations, drawings, and field changes involving structural steel and concrete. To this end I also conducted field walkdowns to analyze and document existing plant conditions and feasibility of changes for numerous structural commodities.

2007-2008

### Civil Engineer/Project Manager at SpecPro ES, LLC

As a project manager I provided oversight of subcontractors for the purging and decommissioning of three 20,000 gallon propane storage tanks. I Worked with engineers and geologists to collect representative groundwater samples for EPA Superfund and US Army Corp of Engineers hazardous site-remediation projects. Coordination with numerous subcontractors and the Corps of Engineers to expedite payment for subcontractor work as it was completed were additional responsibilities. Performed duties as foreman for the construction of a large reinforced concrete pad to heavy industrial equipment.

2006-2007

### Transportation Engineering Contract Employee for Kimley-Horn & Associates

As a transportation engineering contract employee I was responsible to safely collect traffic data in metropolitan areas and was awarded all subsequent traffic data collection contracts in the East Tennessee area. In this role I was also responsible for invoicing, employee scheduling, and project completion with submittals to Kimley-Horn & Associates. Used PETRA modeling program to format and organize traffic data prior to submitting the deliverables. In addition, I hired and trained student employees to ensure task completion.

#### Skills and Associations

**Engineering Skills:** GT STRUDL, STAAD Pro, AutoCAD, Tekla Structures, MathCAD, Microstation, ProjectWise, SmartPlant, MS Office Suite

Codes & Standards: AISC Manual of Steel Construction, ACI 318, AISC N690, ASCE Standards 43, 7, 8, 4, AWS Codes D1.1 and D1.8, International Building Code, AISC Design Guides 1, 9, 24, and 27, OSHA (29CFR1910, 1926)